《曼哈頓計劃》前情提要...
Previously on "Manhattan"...
不管我們在這做什麼
Whatever we're doing here,
告訴我這一切都是值得的
please tell me it's worth it.
我的表妹一家在歐洲...
My cousins in Europe...
我對那兒所發生的一切都無能為力
I can't do anything about what's happening over there.
但你可以
But you can.
在海森堡項目裏的那個內應
The man inside Heisenberg's project,
被處決了
they executed him.
麥格派
Magpie?
你沒跟任何人提起他吧
You didn't tell anyone else about him, did you?
法蘭克一直在給你寄錢嗎
Frank's been sending money?
告訴他他沒什麼好內疚的
Tell him he has nothing to feel guilty about.
法蘭克為什麼會內疚呢
Why would Frank feel guilty?
看來是真的  你現在聽命於奧克利
It's true, you've been listening to Akley.
我不會為了成全法蘭克·溫特的野心
I am not gonna be the last casualty
而成為最後一個犧牲品
of Frank Winter's ego.
我要回家了  查理
I'm going home, Charlie.
軍方不會放你回去
The army won't allow it.
只要我們離婚了他們就會放我走
They will if we're divorced.
瘦子計劃沒希望了
Thin Man is dead.
這項計劃沒有我們不可能完成
This project won't survive without us.
你願意和我合作
You'd work with me?
你已經盡力了  裏德
You did the best you could, Reed.
裏德
Reed!
他們跟我們說只要一天
They told us one day.
已經過了五天了
That was five days ago.
看見上面那個紅章了嗎
See that red stamp?
說明你們的情況比較特殊
That means there are contingencies.
有政府官員在審查你們的申請
Some men from the government have taken an interest in your case.
什麼員  我不明白
What men? I don't understand.
這事我也無能為力
I'm afraid it's out of my hands.
你只能耐心等待
You'll just have to wait.
我填了所有的表格  付了入境費
I filled out the forms. I paid the entry fee.
你們跟我說要付五十美金才能入境
You tell me we need to pay $50 to enter the country.
我們有五萬美金
We have $50,000.
女士
Ma'am.
是叫普爾曼嗎
...Perlman.
據我所知他們有美國人做擔保
I understand that these nice people have an American sponsor.
是的  是這個人
Yes, this is the one.
她說他的名字叫查爾斯·艾薩克
She says his name is Charles Isaacs.
他是位重要人物
He is a very important man.
跟我說說關於艾薩克先生的事
Tell me about Mr. Isaacs.
曼哈頓計劃
第一季 第十三集
Perestroika 變革
本季終
我想自殺的原因總是...
I guess it's always a mystery...
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
一個謎
suicide.
但裏德·奧克利
But Reed Akley?
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用於任何商業盈利行為
你最後一次見他時他看上去如何
How did he seem when you saw him last?
翻譯  阿包  菲力  王二川  木淺薰  蔡茸茸
我不知道
I don't know.
翻譯  小酸奶  抹茶咖啡  小肚腩  持久  迷失綻放
跟往常一樣
The same.
我從未想過
I guess I never realized.
校對  賣竹子換核彈
被瞞在鼓裏就很難
Hard as it is having secrets kept from you...
時間軸  濃子  阿包  言
後期  Sung   精校&總監  麵條打包子
一直保守著這些秘密肯定更難
Keeping them must be harder.
凱莉
Callie!
有人能去開下門嗎
Is anyone planning on getting that?
好吧  我去開
All right, already.
別喊了
Hold your fire.
爸爸
Um, dad?
Dad!
-他的妻子還好嗎  -重要嗎
- How's his wife holding up? - Does it matter?
至少他沒孩子
At least he didn't have children.
事成人人居功  失敗無人關懷
Success has many fathers, but failure is an orphan.
裏德·奧克利要為戰爭史上
Reed Akley was the father
最昂貴的失敗負責
of the most expensive failure in the history of war.
而我要對他負責
I was his father.
瘦子計劃...有什麼問題嗎
There's a-- there's a problem with Thin Man?
裏德·奧克利死了
Reed Akley is dead.
正如你所知道的  瘦子計劃也完了
So is Thin Man, as you well know.
這並不意味著整個計劃都泡湯了
That doesn't mean the project is dead.
-內爆炸彈可以實現  -巴比特跟我說了
- The implosion bomb works. - Babbit told me.
-日落之前給我提交一份書面匯報  -沒問題
- I'll need a written briefing by day's end. - I can do that.
是交給陸軍部的  寫得淺顯一點
It's for the War Department. Use small words.
我們得讓他們放心領導位子會順利交接
We have to reassure them there's continuity of leadership.
我得知道你是否準備好了
I need to know that you're ready.
準備  準備什麼...
Ready? Ready for--
24小時後  戰爭部長要親自接見你
24 hours, you'll be sitting in a room with the Secretary of War.
選你也是無奈之舉
If I could choose anyone else, I would,
但你是唯一一個
but you're the only man
足夠瞭解內爆  可以管理整個項目的人
who knows implosion well enough to run the program.
不管你惹出過什麼麻煩  趕緊擺平
Whatever messes you've made, clean them up.
不能讓白宮知道你搞的爛攤子
Can't have you tracking mud onto the carpet of the Oval Office.
格蘭得回來做我的副手
I'll need Glen back as my number two.
巴比特博士將從項目中隱退
Dr. Babbit will be retiring from the project.
-羅伯特  -他擅用職權
- Robert... - He abused the power of my office.
辜負了我的信任  是他自作自受
Betrayed my trust. That was his choice.
法蘭克·溫特的朋友
Friends of Frank Winter
在這鎮上都待不久  不是嗎
don't have a long shelf life on this Hill, do they?
我並不希望事態如此發展
It's not the way I wanted it.
我也不希望
That makes two of us.
對了  法蘭克
Oh, Frank,
買個梳子好好梳梳頭
buy a comb.
你還願意回來啊
Nice of you to drop in.
我該把你兒子叫醒嗎
Should I wake your son
還是你只是回來換個衣服
or are you just here to change your clothes?
艾比  別這樣
Abby, please.
前兩晚你肯定不止是在辦公室
You can't just hibernate in your office
或是別的地方睡覺這麼簡單吧
or wherever you've spent the last two nights.
-奧克利不在了  -去哪兒了
- Akley's gone. - Where?
他...
He, um...
吞槍自殺了...
put a gun in his mouth and, um...
裏德·奧克利  天哪
Reed Akley? My God.
都是我的錯  艾比
It's my fault, Abby.
-什麼  -是我害他走上絕路的
- What? - I let him paint himself into a corner.
兩個月前我就該去找他  而不是
I should have walked into his office two months ago, instead...
夫人  你丈夫得跟我們走
Ma'am, we're gonna have to borrow your husband.
查理  等等  別抓他
Charlie. Excuse me. No.
-查理  查理  -不會有事的  艾比
- Charlie. Charlie! - It's gonna be fine, Abby.
我要跟我丈夫說話  長官
I need to speak to my husband, Sir.
這只是誤會  艾比
It's just a misunderstanding, Abby.
喬伊  你別進去
Joey, you stay out of there.
不許進去
Do not go in there!
我還得買套新西服
I'll have to get a new suit.
真的要我們接手嗎
We're really taking over?
海倫  你來負責模型設計小組
Helen, you will run the model and design group.
米克斯負責電子部門  福瑞茨負責冶金部
Meeks, the electric division. Fritz, metallurgy.
我有件西裝上衣  但配套的褲子丟了
I had a jacket, but I lost the pants
別的褲子還都配不上
and it doesn't match my other trousers.
戰爭是否終結
The end of the war
可能就掌握在這組裏的五個人的手中了
could be decided by the five people in this group.
我知道自己該怎麼做
I know what my decision is.
海倫  克羅斯利去哪了
Helen, where the hell is Crosley?
我不知道
I don't know.
查理·艾薩克呢
What about Charlie Isaacs?
瘦子那邊
There have been violations
發現了違反任務劃分的行為
of compartmentalization over at Thin Man.
軍方正在清查領導人員
The army is wiping its leadership slate clean.
艾薩克博士
Dr. Isaacs.
請坐
Have a seat.
我之前八個月已經坐得夠久了
I've been sitting for the last eight months.
你這個新人的表現很亮眼啊
Quite a rookie season you've had.
兩個月前你還只是個小研究員
Two months ago you were a towel boy.
如今你卻是裏德·奧克利的秘密武器
Now you're Reed Akley's secret weapon.
準確說是你和那把步槍
Well, you and the rifle.
我很遺憾發生了那種事
I'm sorry to hear the news.
我也是
So was I.
-他為什麼會自殺  -我不知道
- Why did he do it? - I have no clue.
真的嗎
Don't you?
我知道瘦子出了一個技術問題
I understand there was a technical problem with Thin Man.
什麼問題
What kind of problem?
導致戰爭失敗的問題
The kind that loses a war.
奧克利知道嗎
Akley knew?
我們正審核瘦子的相關文件來查明此事
We're auditing Thin Man's files to find out.
發現了一些不能理解的內容
There are some irregularities.
-在奧克利的文件裏嗎  -是你的文件
- In Akley's files? - In yours, actually.
你分配給手下員工的計算任務
The calculations you've been assigning your staff,
似乎基本都和瘦子無關
it's almost as if they have no bearing on Thin Man whatsoever.
在外行人看來可能不能理解
They may look irregular to an untrained eye.
但你的前同事  蘭斯菲爾德博士
But your former colleague, Dr. Lancefield,
算內行了  對吧
he's trained, isn't he?
湯姆·蘭斯菲爾德
Tom Lancefield?
他告訴了我一個離奇的故事
He told me a fascinating story.
他說你蓄謀做到領導位置  旨在毀了整個計劃
Said you'd hotwired the project and were driving it over a cliff.
軍方在他家地板下面找到了遺失的文件
They found stolen files under his floorboards.
他現在可能
He's probably fingered
[美國第34任總統]
連德懷特·艾森豪威爾都拉下水了
Dwight Eisenhower by now.
但時機也太巧了  不是嗎
The timing is curious, though, isn't it?
裏德·奧克利對你委以重任
Reed Akley knights you.
兩個月後
Two months later,
他就躺上瞭解剖台  他的炸彈也玩完了
he's lying on an autopsy table and so is his bomb,
而且所有人
and no one can make heads or tails
都對你簽發過的文件一頭霧水
out of the paper trail coming out of your office.
我是出於謹慎  試圖尋找備用方案
I was exploring alternate theories out of an excess of caution.
有意思的是在一個外行人眼裏
Funny how to an untrained eye
你的謹慎更像是妨害
caution looks like sabotage.
我在努力挽救這個項目
I-- I was trying to save the project.
所以你早就知道瘦子出了問題
So you were aware of a problem in Thin Man.
我們來談談史林默博士
Let's talk about Herr Doktor Schlimmer.
就是麥格派  我們在維爾納·海森堡實驗室的內應
Magpie. Our man inside Werner Heisenberg's lab.
有人走漏消息  害他丟了腦袋
Till somebody talked and he lost his head.
抱歉  你是什麼機構派來的人
I'm sorry, what agency do you represent?
司法部  財政部  陸軍部  移民局
Justice, Treasury, War, Immigration.
你從什麼時候開始
When did you become aware of the existence
知道我們在納粹的炸彈計劃中有內應
of an allied spy in the Nazi's bomb project?
有人嗎
Hello?
羅斯
Rose?
萊莎
Liza.
我以為是司機來了
I thought you were the driver.
我再也忍受不了在這獨自過夜了
I couldn't spend another night here alone.
我要帶裏德回芝加哥
I'm taking Reed back to Chicago.
羅斯  我很抱歉
Rose, I'm so sorry.
有需要我幫忙的嗎
Is there anything I can do?
你贏了  那次的鎮議會
You won. The town council.
壓倒性的勝利
It was a landslide.
那些都不重要
None of that really matters.
他們都錯了
They're wrong, you know?
裏德不會...
Reed didn't--
一定是個意外
Must have been an accident.
一切早就在他掌控之中
He had the world on a string.
他馬上就能結束戰爭帶來和平
He was almost ready to deliver the peace.
萊莎
Liza...
法蘭克對你說過什麼嗎
did Frank say anything to you?
有關裏德的
About Reed?
他說裏德是他見過的
He said that Reed was the most...
最出色的人
brilliant man he'd ever met.
夫人  車就在門口
Ma'am, the car's out front.
照顧好法蘭克
Take care of Frank.
他現在是一把手了
He's on the throne now.
這才是真正害死裏德的東西
That's what really killed Reed, you know?
掌控小玩意的權力
The Gadget.
我不知道要用多少種方式來解釋
I don't know how many different ways I can say this.
即便我以前就知道
Even if I had known about an inside man
在維爾納·海森堡的員工中裏有內應
in Werner Heisenberg's staff--
-其實你不知道  -我確實不知道
- Which you didn't. - Which I didn't.
我絕不可能告訴別人  尤其不會告訴那些納粹
I wouldn't have told a soul, least of all the Nazis.
-我有親戚在歐洲  -在明斯克
- I have family in Europe. - In Minsk.
並不是一個對猶太人特別友善的地方
Not a particularly hospitable corner of the map for Jews.
所謂秘密
The thing about secrets,
就是一旦洩露  就會一發不可收拾
once the genie's loose, you can never put it back in the bottle.
先兩人知道  然後四人  八人  十六人
First two people know, then four, then eight, then 16.
就像連鎖反應  你告訴了某位俄羅斯共產黨員
It's a chain reaction. You tell some Russian apparatchik,
就導致了柏林的某位物理學家
somewhere in Berlin a physicist winds up
只落得頸上空空
in a coffin with extra headroom.
可我怎麼會和俄國人聯繫呢
But why would I talk to the Russians?
因為家人重於一切
'Cause family is everything.
而你有家人在明斯克
And you had family in Minsk.
尤里  一家之主
Yuri, the husband,
他還在那兒  可能已經死了
he's still there and probably dead.
但馬爾嘉和他們的小女兒
But Malka and the little girl,
來到了紐約
they're in New York City.
她們很想見你
And they're very eager to meet you...
她們在美國擔保人
their American benefactor.
她們逃出來了
They made it out?
蘇聯人真是有趣
The Soviets are a funny bunch.
他們可以一槍打死你
They'll put a bullet through your head
然後讓你的妻子來為那顆子彈買單
and send your wife the bill for the ammunition.
但他們還要遵守自己的承諾
And yet they tend to keep their promises
一報還一報
tit for tat.
他們得到了曼哈頓計劃的內線情報
They got an inside line to the Manhattan Project
而你也將家人救出了歐洲
and you -- you got your wife's family out of Europe.
是裏德·奧克利救她們出來的
Reed Akley got them out.
我  我
I, um -- I --
我問過他能不能幫上忙
I asked him if there was anything he could do.
那不如我們叫他來跟你對質一下吧
Well, let's bring him down here so he can confirm your story.
我絕不會洩露軍事機密的
I would never disclose military secrets.
請證明
Prove it.
不
No.
我做不到  我沒法證明
No, I can't. I can't prove it.
就像我沒法證明我不是牙僊一樣
I can't prove that I'm not the tooth fairy either.
證偽是不可能的
You can't prove a negative.
你們科學家不是經常做這種事嗎
You scientists do it all the time.
你們管那叫什麼來著   虛假設
What do you call it? A null hypothesis?
如果你沒法證實你的理論
If you can't prove your theory is valid,
就會設法檢驗相反的理論無法成立
you examine the opposite theory and try to refute it.
讓我們來梳理一下事實吧
Let's look at all the data, you and I.
查爾斯·艾薩克不是間諜  這是虛假設
Charles Isaacs is not a spy. That's our null hypothesis.
如果假設為真  那麼他應該忠於他的祖國
If it were true, we'd expect him to be loyal to his country.
我來這兒正是出於對國家的忠誠
That's why I'm here.
但從你到達的第一天開始
And yet since the day you arrived,
你就一直在質疑這個
you've questioned the ethics of a project
關係到國家存亡的計劃是否道德
undertaken to protect your country from annihilation.
如果查爾斯·艾薩克不是間諜
If Charles Isaacs were not a spy...
聽我說
Listen to me...
那麼他身邊的人應該都是守法公民
I would expect him to associate with law-abiding citizens.
你父親是奧斯卡·艾薩克
Your father is Oscar Isaacs,
前美國社會黨成員
former member of the Socialist Party of America,
現被關押在密蘇里州監獄
current resident of the Missouri State Penitentiary.
我和父親已經多年沒聯繫了
My father and I haven't spoken in years.
而且你和理查德·拉夫羅夫教授熟識
You also are acquainted with a Professor Richard Lavro
正是那個放棄哈佛教授席位
who traded his office at Harvard
加入了斯大林原子彈研究部的人
for one in Stalin's Atomic Research Division,
上次你卻對我隱瞞了此事
an association you misrepresented the last time we met.
如果查爾斯·艾薩克不是間諜
If Charles Isaacs is not a spy,
那麼他應該主動合作  坦白所有
we'd expect him to be forthcoming and cooperative,
但你卻從踏進
and yet you have lied
這扇門起就一直在說謊
since the moment you set foot into this room.
所以我就是你的統一場論嗎  天才
So I'm your unified theory, is that right, genius?
所有的科學失誤  所有洩密事件
That every scientific failure, every intelligence slip up,
都是我一手造成的
I'm singlehandedly responsible?
我可不確定你沒同謀
I'm not so sure it was singlehanded.
普爾曼一家是你妻子的表親吧
The Perlmans are your wife's cousins?
艾比是否也參與其中了呢
What role did Abby play in all of this?
保羅
Paul.
我沒想到你居然知道我住哪
Didn't think you had the first idea where I lived.
我不知道  是海倫告訴我的
I didn't. Helen told me.
是你告訴奧克利我們在利用瘦子的資源嗎
So you told Akley we were siphoning resources from Thin Man?
我沒有
No, I didn't.
所以是他自己猜出來的
He just pieced it together on his own?
不是我們在利用瘦子的資源  法蘭克
We weren't siphoning anything, Frank.
是你和艾薩克  還有海倫
You and Isaacs were. And Helen.
我只是給了奧克利你沒能給我的東西
I just gave Akley what you declined to give me,
真相
the benefit of the truth.
但對他可沒什麼好處  不是嗎
It wasn't too much of a benefit, was it?
你竟敢把他的死怪到我頭上
Don't you dare lay his death at my feet.
孰是孰非都不重要
It doesn't matter now.
從今天開始  這裏的所有人
As of today, all the eyes within these fences
都會為我們小組工作
will be trained on our group.
你是害怕我會說出去  法蘭克
You're afraid I'll talk, Frank.
你來這就是為了這個
That's what you're doing here.
來確保我不會在操場上
To make sure I don't tell any inconvenient tales
說些不合時宜的事
in the schoolyard.
我們要團結一致
We need to stand together.
我父親是名鐵匠  法蘭克
My father was a blacksmith, Frank.
他窮其一生都在打鐵
He spent his whole life hammering iron.
我的人生也本應跟他的一樣
That was supposed to be my life, too.
但是有一天
And then one day,
我讀到一篇關於盧瑟福男爵[原子核物理之父]
I read about Lord Rutherford
把氮原子轉化為氧原子的文章
changing nitrogen into oxygen.
我就下定決心  那才是我的人生
And I thought, that's the life for me.
我要把點石成金變成現實
I can turn my stock into a nobler metal.
但在牛津大學讀書那些年
But all those years at Oxford
周圍都是權貴後裔
surrounded by boy kings--
我絲毫沒有歸屬感
I never belonged.
我怎麼可能融入他們
Of course I didn't.
但是在你的團隊裏  法蘭克
But in your group, Frank,
跟兄弟們和海倫在一起
with the lads, with Helen...
你是內爆小組的一員  保羅
You belong in the implosion group, Paul.
我們是一體的
With us.
不  我曾經以為我是其中一員
No. I thought I did.
但我錯了
I was mistaken.
我答應你保持沉默
You get my silence.
但我要離開
But not me.
艾比
Abby.
你到這來幹什麼  你不應該到這來
What the hell are you... You shouldn't be here.
他們說你要見我
They said you needed to see me.
甚至都不讓我收拾下
They wouldn't even let me clean myself up.
發生什麼事了
What is going on?
他把你帶過來  是為了嚇唬我
He brought you in here to spook me.
他認為我
He thinks I'll, um...
-迫於壓力就會鬆口  -誰
- crack under the pressure. - Who?
你是不是應付不來了
Are you in over your head?
我應不應該告訴我父親  因為
Should I call my father, because--
艾比  相信我
Abby, trust me,
帽子王殿下管不了這件事
this is outside of the Hat King's jurisdiction.
儘管我父親在麻省
Yes, well, my father may be in Massachusetts,
但他跟很多華盛頓身居要職的人關係都很好
but he's on a first-name basis with half of Washington.
查理  維克斯參議員出席了我們的婚禮
Charlie, Senator Weeks was at our wedding.
你回家吧
You need to go home.
憲兵正把家裏翻了個底朝天
MPs are tearing the place apart.
-那些牆還沒倒真是個奇跡  -不
- It's a miracle the walls are still standing. - No.
我是說真正的家  麻省
I mean home. Massachusetts.
是因為蘭斯菲爾德家的事嗎
Is this about the Lancefields?
你的家人安全了
Your family is safe.
什麼
What?
你在歐洲的表親
Your cousins in Europe.
普爾曼一家
The Perlmans.
-他們都死了  查理  -不  沒有
- They're dead, Charlie. - No, no.
她們人在紐約
They're in New York.
也許睡在某個廉價旅店裏
Probably bunked up in some fleabag hotel,
但是她們沒事
but they're fine.
比我們安全
Safer than we are.
現在  某些政府官員心有疑慮
Now, some men from the government are asking questions.
-他們  -他們認為你是間諜
- They... - They think that you're a spy.
認為我出賣了軍事機密
Well, that I traded military secrets.
但你沒有
But you didn't.
對  我沒有  當然沒有
No, I didn't. Of course not.
不管他們認為你做了什麼
Whatever they think you did,
都是法蘭克·溫特讓你做的
Frank Winter made you do it.
你跟他們這麼說
You tell them that.
艾比  那樣你也會被牽連進來
Abby, you'd be implicated, too.
法蘭克知道了
Frank knows.
他知道是你幫我給X工廠打了無人監聽的電話
He knows that you helped me make an unmonitored call to Site X.
他知道是你在蘭斯菲爾德家放了文件
He knows that you put the papers in Lancefield's apartment.
他都知道
He knows.
你可以提出離婚
You can have the divorce.
我不會反對
I won't fight it.
你和喬伊盡可能地遠離這個地方
You and Joey need to get as far away from this place...
-查理  我  -越遠越好
- Charlie, I... - As you can.
-艾比  -好吧
- Abby... - Yes.
-我真的很抱歉  -沒事的
- I am so sorry. - It's all right.
你知道嗎  要是我們當初沒來這
You know, maybe if we never came here...
要是我們待在布魯克萊恩  事情就不會變成這樣
maybe if we stayed in Brookline, things would be different.
-艾比  艾比  -查理  查理
- Abby. Abby. - Charlie. Charlie.
-快走  -查理
- Come on. - Charlie.
-求你們不要帶走他  -會沒事的
- Please don't take him. - Things will be fine.
不要傷害他
Please don't hurt him!
-會沒事的  -不要
- It's gonna be fine. - No.
不要傷害他
Please don't hurt him.
不
No...
格蘭
Glen.
我還以為你會給那些
Figured you'd be trying to teach basic calculus
以前瘦子小組的成員教基礎微積分呢
to the group formerly known as Thin Man.
天知道沒有你我一個人怎麼做得到
God knows how I'll do that without you.
你總有辦法的
Oh, you'll manage.
我估計走之前沒法回趟家了
I doubt I'm gonna make it up to the house before I go.
他們要我馬上搬出基地
They want me off the Hill.
但是  告訴我的教女
But, uh, tell my goddaughter
她的下半輩子
she'll have the rest of her life
可以隨意抽煙喝酒了
for drinking and smoking cigarettes.
我猜哥倫比亞知道系主任要回去了一定很高興
I imagine the Lions will be happy to have their chairman back.
已經退休了
Emeritus.
這段日子早就成了榮譽職稱
Of practically everything these days.
當我們被困在這個沙箱裏時
Anyway, while we've been playing in the sandbox,
哥倫比亞大學已經開始青睞實驗物理了
Columbia has fallen in love with experimental physics.
接下來去哪  芝加哥大學  耶魯大學
Then where? Chicago? Yale?
莫斯科怎麼樣
Moscow?
我不知道
I don't know.
我聽說好多老光棍都在往西走
I hear a lot of old bachelors are heading west.
你應該過得快快樂樂的
You deserve to be happy.
是啊
Yeah.
格蘭  如果有什麼我可以幫忙的
Glen, if there's anything I could do--
二十年前  我以為我是位很棒的物理學家
20 years ago, I thought I was a pretty good physicist,
然後你走進了我的辦公室
then you walked into my office.
該死的大二小毛頭
Goddamn college sophomore.
直到我看了你的研究成果
I didn't know what was missing from my work
才意識到自己研究的問題在哪兒
until I saw it in yours.
相比起來這個項目更需要你  而不是我
This project needs you a lot more than it needs me.
我需要你
I need you.
老實說  我如釋重負啊
Honestly, I'm relieved.
我想總得有人把它造出來
I suppose somebody has to build it,
但我很慶幸世人因此記住的不會是我
but I'm glad it's not gonna be on my tombstone.
-一旦結束了我就打電話給你  -不用了
- I'll call you as soon as it's over. - Don't.
格蘭  真希望我能幫上點什麼忙
Glen, I wish there was something that I could do--
別想魚與熊掌兼得了  法蘭克
Stop trying to have it both ways, Frank.
你是不是好人這無關緊要
It doesn't matter if you're a good man.
說不定好人根本沒法實現內爆模型
Maybe a good man couldn't have made implosion work.
重要的是你將是終結這場戰爭的人
All that matters is that you are the man to end this war.
孰是孰非等一切塵埃落定後由上帝來裁決
Let God do the accounting when it's over.
是啊
Yeah.
昨天這的所有人都還不知道我們是誰
Yesterday nobody on this hill even knew who we were.
不管怎麼樣  我支持金妮的工作
Anyway, I do support Jeannie's work,
我只是覺得作為
I just don't think it's right
管理鈽的頭兒仍然單身不太好
for the new head of the plutonium division to be unmarried.
咱們的工資都會有小幅度的增長
We're all gonna get tiny, little pay bumps
我敢保證一個多月後我就有錢買戒指了
and I'm sure I'll have enough for a ring in a month or so.
-恭喜你啊  -小心點
- Hey, mazel tov. - Watch out.
過不了多久你的門檻就會被求親的姑娘們踩爛了
The ladies are gonna be beating a path to your door in no time.
米克斯先生嗎
Mr. Meeks?
你是說米克斯主任嗎
You mean Division Head Meeks?
這傢伙晉陞的速度比鐵路股還快  親愛的
This guy's rising faster than railroad stock, darling.
總機有電話找你
There was a call at the switchboard.
請節哀順變
I'm sorry.
這可是一大飛躍啊
Wow, this is a step up.
我一直在努力
You know, I've learned not to grow too attached
不對辦公室產生感情
to offices one way or the other.
我只要有扇門就很滿足了
Well, I'm just looking forward to having a door.
等有人天天來找你就不這麼想了
Wait till people start knocking on it.
我母親昨天去世了
My mother died yesterday.
不過是半夜以後的事  所以有可能是今天
Well, it was after midnight, so maybe it was today.
班戈市總醫院的護士也不清楚具體時間
The nurses at Bangor General didn't know which.
老天  吉姆  我很遺憾
Jesus, Jim, I'm sorry.
是因為意外嗎
Was it unexpected?
身為小兒麻痹癥患者卻活過了半百
Well, she made it into her 50s with polio,
已經很了不起了  對吧
so that's something, right?
等你回來就能看到你的新辦公室了
Well, your new office will be waiting for you when you get back.
我現在不能走
Oh, well, I can't leave now.
特別是現在這種狀況
Not with everything that's going on.
不管怎麼說  陸軍絕不會
Anyway, the army would never
這麼快就同意給我通行證的
grant me a pass on such short notice.
日落前你就能拿到
You'll have one by sunset.
坐進這個辦公室就可以享有一些特權
Turns out this office comes with a few privileges.
謝謝你  法蘭克
Thanks, Frank.
我會快去快回的  我發誓
I won't be gone long. I swear.
你母親還在世嗎  法蘭克
Is your mother still alive, Frank?
我不知道
I don't know.
她把一切都坦白了
She told me everything.
艾比在哪兒
Where's Abby?
女人總是把孩子的安危放在第一位
Women are always quick to protect their children.
丈夫在她們心中就沒有這種地位
Husbands tend not to get the same treatment.
你妻子就在隔壁
Your wife is sitting in the next room.
她把你的所作所為和動機都告訴我了
She told me everything you've done and why.
你胡說
That's bullshit.
沒人會去責怪一個
No one can blame a man
即想將妻子的家人救出納粹的魔掌
for trying to save his wife's family from the Nazis
又想挽救自己婚姻的男人
and his marriage all in one fell swoop.
艾比什麼都不會告訴你
Abby would not have told you anything.
一旦有了背叛  就會越走越遠
Betrayal gets easier and easier and easier.
畢竟  她這幾個月來都在背著你
After all, she has been betraying you for months
和鄰居交往
with your neighbor.
在蘭斯菲爾德的床上做愛
Making love in Lancefield's bed.
還有你的床上
In your bed.
現在我可以肯定你是在撒謊
Well, now I know that you're lying.
她討厭蘭斯菲爾德
She hated Lancefield.
她是不會靠近他的
She wouldn't go anywhere near him.
當然  你說得對
Yes, well, of course you're right.
但事實是  他的外籍妻子
But you see, that foreign wife of his,
也是一個有故事的人
she had an interesting story, too.
其中就包括在你工作時
One about romancing your wife
和你妻子談情說愛
while you were at work.
你妻子是個難捉摸的女人  艾薩克博士
Your wife is a complicated woman, Dr. Isaacs.
但一旦當她意識到
But as soon as she realized
她有可能失去她的兒子
that she might very well lose her son,
讓她坦白你的所作所為就很簡單了
getting her to admit what you've done was simple.
我不相信
I don't believe you.
但你已開始相信
But you do.
你正在回想你每次去打橋牌
You're thinking back to every bridge game,
出去喝酒
every martini.
每次你妻子...
Every time your wife...
每次你妻子告訴你  她要去
every time your wife told you she was going over there
向那個女人再借點麵粉
to borrow another cup of flour from that woman.
你應該就能一件接一件地接受
So you might as well start admitting
我告訴你的那些事實
what I already know fact by fact!
我跟你無話可說  混蛋
We're done here, asshole.
其實我們倆的工作沒多大差別
You know, our businesses are not so different.
人心中壓抑著的秘密
A secret trapped inside a man
就像原子核中蘊含的能量
is just like the energy trapped in an atom.
都渴望被釋放  當然了
It wants to be released. Of course,
我擁有的資源可跟你沒法比
I don't nearly have the resources you do.
我手下只有幾名一片赤子之心的人
Myself, I've only had a few dedicated patriots,
但是他們  他們發明了一些
but they... they have developed
非常行之有效的技術
some very advanced techniques
來讓別人開口招供
to convince a man to talk.
什麼  你打算對我嚴刑拷打嗎
What, you're gonna torture me?
1929年的《日內瓦公約》...
The Geneva Convention of 1929--
[《日內瓦公約》的一部分  主要內容為保護戰俘]
你要去的地方
Where you're going,
根本不受公約約束
people don't concern themselves with convention.
其他的所有船員
It is feared that the other members of the crew
可能早已葬身海底
have been drowned.
不斷有人報告  目擊到德國潛艇
With the view of the established presence
在周圍地區出現
of German submarines in this vicinity,
毫無疑問
there can be no reasonable doubt
艦上所塗的旗幟是
as to the identity of the flag...
-你一定是艾比吧  -是的
- Hi. You must be Abby. - Yes.
你丈夫在嗎
Is your husband here?
-我叫海倫·普林斯  是他的同事  -我知道
- I'm Helen Prins. I work with him. - I know who you are.
艾薩克博士今天在家休假嗎
Did Dr. Isaacs stay home today?
我們一直在技術區找他
We've been looking for him in the tech area.
-我們  -是緊急情況
- We? - It's urgent.
公事還是私事
Business or pleasure?
抱歉親愛的  門都鎖了  我來了
I'm sorry, sweetie, all the doors are locked. I'm coming.
我的小寶貝  來媽媽抱
Hello, my life! Come here. Oh!
今天蕩鞦韆蕩到了多高呀
How high did you get on the swings this time?
可高了
I get so high.
-你先帶他進房間吧  -我蕩得特別高
- Could you excuse us just for a minute? - I get super high.
這麼高啊  快去你房間  我收拾過了
So high! You run on in there. I cleaned your room up.
我蕩鞦韆蕩得特別高
I get super high on the swings.
-你該走了  -我真的得見他
- I think you should leave. - I really need to see him.
那你來晚了一步
Well, you're a little late.
憲兵今天早上把查理帶走了
MPs came for Charlie this morning.
為什麼
Why?
因為他們認為這位來自東聖路易斯的猶太人
Because they think that a Jew from East St. Louis
把軍事情報洩露給了想要消滅我們的敵人
is passing military secrets to people who want to exterminate us.
這鎮上可不只你一個人
And you are not the only person on this Hill
想要把我丈夫從他家人身邊奪走
who's trying to take my husband away from his family.
你想要哪本書
Which book did you pick?
那本看起來不錯
That looks like a good one.
法蘭克
Frank!
你知道奧克利還在讀本科時
You know, Akley derived a new space-time geometry
就推導出了新的時空幾何嗎
when he was still in college?
是查理的事
Um, it's Charlie.
我早跟你說過了
You heard me earlier.
這裏沒有他的位置
There is no place for him here.
他們會把他送出基地
They're shipping him off the Hill.
他早就知道後果
He knew the risks.
一開始他來找我的時候心裏就清楚
He came to me with eyes wide open.
你到底想要怎麼樣  海倫
What do you want, Helen?
你想要我們三個人
Do you want all three of us
都因為違反任務劃分規定而被罰嗎
to go down for breaking compartmentalization?
你不明白  他們認為他是叛徒
You don't understand. They think he's a traitor.
從沒想過自己會說這種話
Never thought I'd say it,
但我會想念這個破屋子的
but I'm gonna miss this shithole.
你也會想的  等著吧
You're gonna miss it, too. Just watch.
你將擁有一支博士大軍供你支配
You'll have an army of PhDs at your beck and call,
辦公桌像斯圖貝克裝甲車那麼大
a desk the size of a Studebaker.
到時你會希望你依然在這間小屋裏
You'll wish you were back in this closet with six guys
只有六個人  還要在信封背面打草稿
and a theory written on the back of an envelope.
你不欠我的  法蘭克
You don't owe me anything, Frank.
不是你命令我去盜取論文
You didn't force me to take those papers.
如果你沒把我供出去
If you hadn't turned me over,
內爆計劃就會泡湯
the project would be dead in the water.
而且最終軍方還是會找上我
Chances are the army would have caught up with me anyway
我還是一樣的結局
and I'd be sitting in the same place.
你也不虧欠艾薩克
You don't owe Isaacs anything either.
你知道這個月的行動中
You know how many American soldiers
死了多少美國士兵嗎
were killed in action this month?
4343人
4,343.
將近是去年同期的四倍
Nearly four times as many as the same month last year.
再算上在戰場上重傷
Add another 503 who died later
之後不治身亡的503人
from injuries sustained on the battlefield,
還有61人失蹤  再加上因
plus 61 missing and reported dead--
友方誤傷  意外  疾病而死亡的
friendly fire, accidents, disease--
這些人一共是1817人
that's another 1,817.
總共是多少人呢
All together, that's, what?
6724人
6,724 lives.
再算上英國人的話  數字還要翻倍
Add the Brits, the number doubles.
再算上蘇聯  他們可是相當拚命
Throw in the Soviets-- they're overachievers--
190254人
190,254.
德軍死亡人數為41200
Germans, 41,200.
日本  澳大利亞  波蘭  法國
Japan, Australia, Poland, France.
保守估計  一年有一千萬人喪生
Conservatively, let's say 10 million deaths in a year.
那就是每月833000人
833,000 a month.
每天27700人
27,700 a day.
每小時11057人
11,057 an hour.
你想要我怎麼做
What do you want me to do?
沒錯
Exactly.
多一個又何妨
What's one more?
我愛你
I love you.
我也愛你
I love you, too.
怎麼了
What's wrong?
我們在造原子彈
We're building an atomic bomb.
通過引發鏈式反應
It'll set off a chain reaction
爆炸時產生的威力
that will explode with the power
相當於兩萬噸TNT炸藥
of 20,000 tons of TNT.
兩萬噸
20,000 tons?
足夠將數座城市從地圖上抹去
Powerful enough to wipe cities off the map.
還有城市中的所有居民
Cities full of people.
孩子
Children.
不  軍方會把它
No, the army will detonate
投到不會引起傷亡的地方
it someplace where it can't hurt anyone.
等軸心國看到炸彈的威力
And when the Axis sees what we're capable of,
他們將別無選擇
they'll have no choice.
不得不投降
They will have to surrender.
以後也再也不會有戰爭
And then there will never be another war.
這就是我們在圍牆後面的秘密
That's what we're doing behind those fences.
我們在書寫時代的新篇章
We're writing the prologue to a new era.
書寫和平之史
The history of peace.
誰的孩子會死在戰爭的最後一刻
分秒必爭
-你看見了嗎  -不確定
- You see that? - Not sure.
帶過來
Bring it around.
檢查一下
Run a check-up.
托爾文
Tolvin.
每位乘客都必須出示身份證件
We need ID from every passenger.
你們還需要驗明亨利·斯汀森的身份嗎
You need ID from Henry Stimson?
-又一個書獃子嗎  -是戰爭部長
- Another egghead? - The Secretary of War.
走吧
Okay, let's go.
放行  走吧
Let 'em through. Let's go.
安全
Clear!
奧本海默博士
Dr. Oppenheimer.
菲捨先生
Mr. Fisher.
我本想說你破壞了我的胃口
I'd say you spoiled my appetite,
不過裏德·奧克利比你更先一步
but Reed Akley beat you to it.
有個人事問題我們需要討論一下
There's a personnel issue we need to discuss.
就現在
Right now.
起來
Get up.
等軸心國看到炸彈的威力
When the Axis sees what we're capable of,
他們將別無選擇
they'll have no choice.
不得不投降
They will have to surrender.
以後也再也不會有戰爭
And then there will never be another war.
這就是我們在圍牆後面的秘密
That's what we're doing behind those fences.
我們在書寫時代的新篇章
We're writing the prologue to a new era.
書寫和平之史
The history of peace.
-部長先生  -奧本海默博士
- Mr. Secretary. - Dr. Oppenheimer.
上次讓我等這麼久
The last time anybody kept me waiting this long,
可是發生政變的時候
there was a coup d'etat.
還不是滴血未流的政變
And not a bloodless one.
對不起
My apologies.
有些重要的事情不得不處理
We had to dot a few Ts and cross a few Is.
-您這一路飛過來還順利嗎  -沒有墜毀
- How was your flight? - It didn't crash.
應該知足了
Well, to small mercies.
我倒是希望墜毀了
I wish it had.
這樣我就不用告訴羅斯福
I wouldn't have to tell Roosevelt
他賭上了整個白宮的前途就換得了幾顆魔豆
that he mortgaged the White House for a handful of magic beans.
我同意這事很令人失望
I grant you this is a disappointment.
你讓美國總統聽取了你那
You sold the President of the United States
《巴克·羅傑斯》般的幻想
a "Buck Rogers" Fantasy.
[美國科幻電影]
你同他握了手  告訴他
You shook his hand and told him
項目的設計被托付給了
the design was entrusted
擁有全國最頂尖頭腦的人
to one of the best minds in the country.
結果現在他的頭腦
And now that mind
全塗在克萊斯勒汽車的儀表盤上
is getting sponged off the dashboard of a Chrysler.
斯汀森部長  請容我解釋...
Secretary Stimson, if I may...
我們有備用計劃
There is a backup plan.
我們保留了第二組的設計
We kept a second design team alive
-以防發生這樣的情況  -內爆那組嗎
- for circumstances just like these! - The implosion group?
那就是你他媽的靈丹妙藥嗎
That's your goddamn panacea?
你自己告訴過我那是天方夜譚
You told me yourself it's science fiction.
現在不是了
Not anymore.
內爆組的負責人
The director of the implosion group
是這鎮上最有智慧的人
is one of the brightest lights on this Hill.
他幾乎獨立地把物理問題解決了
He solved the physics almost singlehandedly.
我會讓他親自給你介紹相關細節
I'll let him walk you through the details himself.
這位是查爾斯·艾薩克博士
This is Dr. Charles Isaacs.
法蘭克·溫特發生什麼事了
What happened to Frank Winter?
等軸心國看到炸彈的威力
When the Axis sees what we're capable of,
他們將別無選擇
they'll have no choice.
不得不投降
They will have to surrender.
以後也再也不會有戰爭
And then there will never be another war.
這就是我們在圍牆後面的秘密
That's what we're doing behind those fences.
我們在書寫時代的新篇章
We're writing the prologue to a new era.
書寫和平之史
The history of peace.
我走過歪路
I've made mistakes.
做了很多我羞於啟齒的事
I've done things I'm not proud of,
但我發誓  我做這些事時都是為了你和凱莉
but I swear, I did all of it with you and Callie in mind.
幾個月前
A few months ago,
另一個設計組的物理學家來找我
a physicist from another design group came to me
告訴我他的模型不會成功
and he told me that his model wasn't going to work.
我向他透露了我曾誓要保密的信息
I revealed information that I'd been sworn to keep secret,
告訴他在德國的原子彈計劃中有我們的內應
that we had spy inside the German atomic project
而且維爾納·海森堡領先了我們好幾個月
and that Werner Heisenberg was months ahead of us.
我知道靠陸軍和白宮
I knew the army and the White House
絕不可能讓計劃步入正軌  所以
would never right the ship on their own, so
我和裏德·奧克利開始秘密謀劃
Reed Akley and I engaged in a secret conspiracy
利用他組內的資源來做內爆
to co-op the resources of his group for implosion.
奧克利給查理·艾薩克升職是想掩蓋我們的蹤跡
Akley promoted Charlie Isaacs to cover our tracks.
如果事情東窗事發就由他頂罪
Set him up in case we ever got caught.
諷刺的是...
The irony is...
想要實現內爆的唯一方法
the only way we were able to crack implosion
就是偷用他論文裏的理論
is by stealing the theory from a paper he wrote.
現在奧克利死了
Now that Akley's dead,
那可憐的孩子被情報部門抓了起來
G-2s got that poor kid locked up.
他們以為他是間諜
They think he is a spy,
其實他毫不知情
but he had no idea.
我幫不了他  但為了實現這個項目
There's nothing I can do but stay the course
為了人類的未來  我只能堅持到底
for the good of the project, for the sake of the future.
犧牲小我  保全大我
We sacrifice the few to save the many.
你應該把他告訴你的都記下來
No, you gotta write down what he tells you.
他是醫生
He's the doctor.
好吧  那...
Well, that's, uh--
如果你不謹遵醫囑  確實就會那樣
that's what happens if you don't keep it elevated.
好吧  你聽我說
Yeah. Oh, listen, listen.
我得...我得掛了
I gotta-- I have to go,
但我...我很快會再打給你  好嗎
but I-- I will call you again soon, okay?
好  我也愛你  媽媽
Yeah. I love you, too, Mom.
借過
Excuse me.
意見分歧...
Differences of opinion...
正如查爾斯·達爾文的真知灼見
As Charles Darwin so ably said...
謹記歷史
Gone but not forgotten.
他們說過我不需要親自來會面
They said I wouldn't have to meet in person.
除非有突發情況
Only under extraordinary conditions.
-事態已改變  -變化無處不在
- Things have changed. - They're changing everywhere.
現在的研發重點是內爆
Implosion is taking center stage.